We've caught the ire of a troublesome foe.
There is only on type of
dragon that breathes fire.
The masters of the Kurogane Mountains...
The flame dragons—
a strain of true dragons—
the Guren Nairi!
A true dragon? Then it's as
dangerous as a Morisuberi?
Yes. The difference being...
This one is neither wounded,
like the Morisuberi was,
nor do we have a group
of over ten warriors!
If we face it head-on you and I may
survive, but Malcius and Cersei will die!
Die?!
Is there anything we can do? Does the
Echo Dragon breathe fire as well?
This spirit is the embodiment
of our yearning for flight.
And flight is the only thing it offers.
It seems we have no choice but
to land and face it in battle.
Two against a fire dragon is madness!
You don't even have a helmet!
The best choice is to flee.
A fire dragon shouldn't take any interest
in a mock dragon in the first place.
Why is this happening?
What was that?!
The Quefto's anti-dragon guns.
They don't seem to be working!
A distraction is all we need!
We're landing!
The Warrior Princess and the Barbaric King
Dying! I'm dying!
Lord Thundering Voice, are you all right?
I appreciate the assist!
But given who our foe is,
I don't like our odds.
The sooner we lose it, the better.
Understood. Everyone,
leave the guns and clear out!
Withdraw into tunnel four!
This way, ladies.
But...
You won't wanna look at it!
Have a taste of Quefto hunter technology!
Sera! Run!
Sera! Hold your breath and get down!
I think we managed to get away.
So it seems.
Are you hurt, Sera?
No, thanks to you.
But what about you?
Considering what happened.
Just a bit singed. Nothing serious.
Lady Serafina!
Are you two all right?
I'm glad you're all unhurt, too.
Have to say, when the watchman came to
sound the alert, I was really shocked.
We would've experienced losses without
the Quefto's support. I'm grateful.
Is it rare to run into those things?
Usually. They tend to keep to
the inside of the crater...
I would've never expected one
this far down the mountain.
I mean, who knows what goes
on in a dragon's head?
For now, let's be grateful
that everybody survived.
You're right.
And here we are.
And this is the dwarves' village?
Welcome to the home of the
Quefto, Furnace Ridge!
To bore so cleanly into
the foot of a mountain...
I can't imagine the technology
and effort that was involved.
Kinda hard to resist being proud,
when you put it that way.
After all, there's nothing we Quefto
enjoy more than digging and research.
I see. That is very dwarf-like.
I should've given my name earlier.
It's Serafina de Lavillant.
The way you blinded the
dragon was brilliant.
Aw, you don't have to be
so formal with your praise,
you're making me feel itchy.
Don't worry about manners with me.
My name is Kimaki. It's nice to meet you.
Right. It's a pleasure, Sir Kimaki.
Aw, don't call me sir!
All right, I figure swapping names might
be a sign. I'll show our guests around!
No fair, Kimaki.
So jealous.
First come, first served!
You're just gonna get lost, anyway!
Yeah, if you show them around,
we might never see them again!
It's a shame after
exchanging names, but...
it's really hard to tell them apart.
It's so hot...
and what's this strange smell?
It's sulfur.
Sulfur? Like what's used in gunpowder?
I believe I read about it in
a military textbook once.
m 10 0 l 185 0 l 195 10 l 195 65 l 185 75 l 185 75 l 10 75 l 0 65 l 0 10
It's actually hydrogen sulfide
that has a strong odor;
solid sulfur is odorless.
Here we are, folks!
Say hello to the source of the
Quefto settlement's hot springs!
I-It really is natural hot water.
I-It's so fantastical!
Is this your first time at a hot spring?
I'd been told about them, but...
Well, as you can see, it's boiling hot...
Over there, we cool it
down to be just right.
Sera. I'll see you later.
Right, of course we'd separate here...
Were you hoping to bathe with Master Veor?
I-I said no such thing!
It's Quefto culture.
For whatever reason,
they have separate changing areas
and entrances for men and women.
I find your lack of pretension
to be much stranger.
Right this way.
Maybe it's because it's for dwarves,
but the ceiling is awfully low.
Everything is made of metal.
Wood long enough for
construction is pretty valuable
because of how much trouble
it is to bring it in.
But there's a ton of stone and metal,
so we naturally ended up living
in these kinds of buildings.
I suppose that's simply
the regional flavor.
I can help you take your armor off, Sera.
Me too!
Yes, please.
But a hot spring, eh?
A natural bath... I can only
wonder what it must feel like.
What happened to men and women bathing
separately?! And you're being so brazen!
Well, Kimaki, even if you are a child...
watching someone get undressed is a bit...
H-Hang on a sec!
I wonder if my gear
muffled my voice some...
That's better, isn't it?
Wh-What?! You still don't believe me?
How about this, then?!
She's a girl?!
"Girl?" I actually turned
55 this year, y'know.
Fifty...?! You're older?!
Well, in Cornem years,
it'd be more like 20.
Another shocked westerner told me
I looked like a kid before.
We don't all have beards, y'know!
Don't make assumptions!
I-It's more based off of an
old story about your kind...
There's a good chance our scarves are
where the beard stories came from, then.
Considering where we live, it's important
for everyone to have protection
against poison gas and dust.
I suppose stories that get passed
down do have that tendency.
The way you're reacting...
It's been a while.
You knew this was going to happen
and didn't say anything, didn't you?
It reminds me of when
Master Veor first brought you in!
But why were you staring at
Lady Serafina as she was changing?
I was looking at that.
My armor?
Miss Sera...
Not that I need repayment
for the hospitality, but...
Would it be okay if I took apart and
did some upkeep on your armor...?
Uh... if you're going to maintain it,
I'd honestly be willing to pay you.
I couldn't ask for that!
Because...
'Cuz...
It'd be rude of me not to lay
hands on such a sexy work of art!
Sh-She's a woman of particular tastes!
Point being, we're all slaves
to our passions down here.
Unique works of craftsmanship,
the study of technology
and rare materials,
even science in the broad sense...
We crave to learn all we can about
anything that catches our interest!
And whenever we meet someone who gives
us a chance to indulge our curiosity,
we love to host them!
Kimaki...
Understood. Study it as much as you want.
Yay!
Seriously?!
Look at it shine!
Amazing!
Damn!
Thanks a bunch, Crystal Helmet!
I'll be along to get a feel later!
What happened to the
separation of sexes?
It's huge!
H-How much firewood
would this luxury cost?
It really is a natural bath.
Does the water seem cloudy to you?
Those are crystals from melted sulfur.
There's sulfur in the water?!
It's a good thing!
Medicinal Usage for Sulfur Springs:
It helps with stamina recovery,
healing cuts, burns, and bad circulation.
- Chronic skin disease
- Chronic gynopathy
- Cuts
- Lifestyle-related diseases
It's supposedly great for the skin, too.
We owe it all to the sulfur!
Th-Then this whole
thing is a medicinal bath?
I suppose it is.
And it's all natural...!
For your information, these waters have
been flowing for at least 2000 years.
That's longer than Illdoren has exited...
Maybe it's best to not think about it.
This is fantastic!
It's certainly different from
washing off in rivers or lakes.
The last time I came here was with the
great chief's wife, and it's still good.
You came with Resia?
Can she use the Echo Dragon too?
Yes, she certainly can.
But how...?
You earn the right to summon it
by defeating a dragon
on your own, apparently.
I'm sure you know how
competitive she can be.
She couldn't resist the chance
to prove herself to a spirit.
A symbol of strength... like the
dragon knights out of a fairy tale!
I want that, too!
No, it's a bad idea.
Even for someone who was able to fight
a dragon with a pair of fire tongs,
it's dangerous!
It's dangerous?!
Wanting to hunt a
dragon single-handedly...
You Cornem sure like to live on the edge.
Look at that.
Feels nice, doesn't it?
I know that we're underground,
but it's still fairly bright.
Like looking at a starry sky.
That shine is coming from the True Silver.
All of that is mythril?!
Just a pinch of it, really.
True Silver glows because it's
affected by the volcano's willpower.
It's gentler than sunlight,
and valuable to us since we
don't do well with bright light.
That boulder over there
is also True Silver.
It hasn't been refined,
so it's a bit cloudy...
But if a Cornem warrior like you,
Miss Sera, channels her willpower
through it, it'll light up!
I see! Okay!
Let's try it right now!
But that's—
Oh, well.
When I touched the stone...
I don't know how to describe
what it made me feel deep inside.
It wasn't like the willpower that
is channeled through a weapon...
Or the curiosity I felt
just a few moments ago...
Nostalgia so strong as to
bring tears to the eyes...
Longing?
What was that?! Is the heat getting to me?
How can I yearn for scenery
I've never seen before?
S-Sera?
Ve..o...r...?
I-I thought you were somewhere else?!
I told you that the changing
rooms are separate...
Then everyone is funneled
into the same baths?!
Get away from her, barbarian!
The only way those two will get closer
is if "accidents" like
these keep happening.
Wait, they're not together?
I had the wrong idea...
And, uh, I must say...
You are one bold woman!
A dragon?!
Wh-Why is it even bigger?!
Lady Serafina!
I will defend your virtue!
Even if I am engaged to him,
I feel that, as a maiden, I lost
something irreplaceable today...
Where's your armor?
The Quefto took it.
How's Malcius doing?
I think she got overheated,
in more ways than one.
Lady Serafina...
I can't deny that I got
a bit overheated, myself.
Is that from earlier?!
That's "a bit singed"?
He was burned protecting me.
Veor... you really are impressive.
She noticed...
I can never seem to impress
in the way I intend to.
But you're no less impressive for it.
Here you are, Lord Thunder
Voice and his party!
Our village's specialty dishes!
Boiled hot springs crab,
alcohol-steamed mountain snails...
and the local staple,
hillside potato mochi!
Dwarven cuisine!
The hot springs crabs live in the
hot springs, as the name suggests,
which gives them a unique aroma,
but they're delicious!
The mountain snails are a kind of
snail that you can find in these parts.
After a preparatory boiling,
you take out the innards,
and then steam the flesh with alcohol.
Snails...?
The hillside potatoes grow all around
the mountain in huge amounts,
so apart from being a staple food,
we use it to make our alcohol.
Tell me, Sera,
what is the the drink that the Quefto
prefer in your western stories?
Dwarven fire wine?!
You actually have some?!
You bet we do!
What a beautiful copper-gold color...
And I don't think I've ever smelt
such strong spirits before!
The distilling process for pharmacology
was how we learned how to make it.
So deliciously spicy!
Try this. It goes well with the wine.
Good! Fantastic!
Try this, too.
Gladly!
Every single food I've tried is amazing!
Something is strange with this land!
Here.
A sip of fire wine, and then...
It's so good!
I think that incident
had a positive effect.
Naked intimacy leading
to new developments...!
Veor, I want to try the potato mochi next!
Chew slowly, so you don't choke.
Give me another, Veor!
Translation: Lee Francis
Timing: Andy Ellis
Editing: Zachary Carlysle
Quality Control: Salem Alabanza
Translation Check: Sho Stifler
I must say, I may have overeaten a bit.
Four crabs, twelve mountain snails,
and nine pieces of
potato mochi... is a bit?
We were just glad you seemed to like it.
We appreciate the heartfelt feast, Kimaki.
I bathed in the hot springs
and ate my fill.
Now it's time for the objective of
this trip—collecting my helmet!
Off we go to the dwarven workshop!